Register of the Joseph Freeman papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1915-1965
  - Zelomek, A. W., 1945-1946. (Folder 36)
  - Zerner, Charles, 1939 (Folder 37)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS (POETRY), 1915-1965
  Holographs, drafts, and printed copies of poetical writings by Joseph Freeman, with related notes, correspondence, and other material, arranged chronologically by date of publication, or, that failing, by date of composition.
  NOTE: This file contains poetical works by Freeman, with the exception of "Hurrah for Everything!" ("Corrido"), because of its relationship to a larger set of prose works; writings on poetry in prose; and many rough notes and drafts which probably include material relating to the development of poems. All these items are located in the subsequent series, SPEECHES AND WRITINGS (PROSE) FILE.
  - General
    - General
      - Correspondence, 1921-1965 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Miscellany. Lists, prefaces, and fragments, undated (Folder 2)
    - Undated
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Uncertain attribution (Folder 4)
    - 1915-1929 (Folder 5-11)
    - 1930-1952 (Box 44, Folder 1-11)
    - 1953-1955 (Box 45, Folder 1-6)
    - 1956-1961 (Box 46, Folder 1-7)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 47, Folder 1-7)
    - 1963-1965 (Box 48, Folder 1-7)
  - "Don Quixote," Collected poems. Typescript, undated (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - "Slaves," in Manuel Gomez, ed., Poems for Workers, Printed copy, undated (Folder 2)
  - Collected poems, Typescript, 1918-1922. (Folder 3)
  - Collected poems, Typescript, 1918-1927. (Folder 4)
  - "Don Giovanni," Collected poems. Typescript, 1921. (Folder 5)
  - Collected poems, Typescript, 1921-1934. (Folder 6)
  - "Felix Dzerszinski," Rote Jahre, Printed copies (in German and English), 1926 August 19 (Folder 7)
  - "Notes for a Poem," New Masses, Printed copy, 1927 June (Folder 8)
  - "Sermons and Stones," Collected poems. Typescript and letter, 1931 (Folder 9)
  - "East River Blues," Printed copy, 1931 February 4. (Folder 10)
  - "Death of a Revolutionist," Rebel Poet, Typescripts (in German and English) and printed copy, 1931 August - September (Folder 11)
  - "Six Poems," Dynamo, Printed copy and clipping, 1934, 1934 January (Folder 12)
  - "Beat, Drums of the World," Daily Worker, Printed copy, 1934 February 10 (Folder 13)
  - "Four Poems," Partisan Review, Printed copy, 1934 February - March (Folder 14)
  - "The Crossing," New Masses, Typescripts and printed copy, 1934 March 27. (Folder 15)
  - "Peasant Correspondence," Daily Worker, Printed copy, 1934 June 30 (Folder 16)
  - "Ballad of Tampa," Partisan Review, Typescripts and printed copies, 1934 June-July (Folder 17)
  - "The Stroke of Noon," Collected poems. Typescript, 1944. (Folder 18)
  - "Prelude," Collected poems. Typescript, 1944-1956 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Collected poems, Typescripts, 1947. (Folder 2)
  - "The Rainbow," Collected poems. Typescript, 1947. (Folder 3)
  - "Spring Came on Forever " 1948. Collected poems. Typescript and letters toJohn Farrar and another (Folder 4)
  - Untitled New Year's toast, Printed copy, 1949 December 28-29 (Folder 5)
  - "On the Jaguar," Nation, Letter to the editor (poem). Typescripts, correspondence with Carey McWilliams, and printed copy, 1954, 1954 June 5. (Folder 6)
  - "In Memoriam," Tribute to Vito Marcantonio. Typescripts, 1954 August (Folder 7)
  - Collected poems, Typescript, 1955 (Folder 8)
  - "The Bow of Burning Gold," Collected poems. Typescript fragments and drafts, 1956-1961 (Folder 9-12)
  - "The Bow of Burning Gold" (Box 51, Folder 1-5)
  - Letter to the editor, New Leader, (date written). Relates to political struggles in the Soviet Union. Typescripts, 1957 July 8 (Folder 6)
  - "Medea at Corinth," Collected poems. Typescripts and letter, 1957-1961 (Folder 7)
  - "East River Anthology [1958]," Typescripts, 1958 March (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - "East River Rock and Roll," Typescripts, 1958 March-April (Folder 2)
  - "Ajax," Typescripts, holographs, and notes, 1961 (Folder 3-5)
  - "A New Earth," Collected poems. Typescript, 1961 (Folder 6)
  - "A Time to Love," Collected poems. Typescript and letter, 1961 (Folder 7-12)
  - "The View from Outer Space," Collected poems. Typescript, 1961. (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - "Sail Forth, Voyager!" Collected poems. Typescript, 1961 April-May (Folder 2)
  - "Adventure in Our Time," Collected poems. Typescript, 1961 May. (Folder 3)
  - "The Fire is Falling," Collected poems. Typescript fragments and drafts, holographs, and notes, 1961-1963 (Folder 4-8)
  - "The Diamond Scepter," Typescript, 1962 February (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Collected poems, Typescripts and holographs, 1962 Fall (Folder 2)
  - "East River Anthology " 1963. Typescripts (Folder 3)
  - "Fair Is My Love," Collected poems. Typescript, 1964 (Folder 4)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS (PROSE), 1912-1965
  Holograph, typescript, and printed copies of prose writings by Joseph Freeman, with related notes, press releases, memoranda, correspondence, and printed matter. Includes material ghostwritten for others. Arranged chronologically by date of publication, or, that failing, by date of composition.
  - General
    - General
      - General. Contract and receipts, 1937-1964 (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - Epigraphs and quotations., undated (Folder 2)
      - Lists (Folder 3)
        Includes pseudonyms used in fiction? SEE ALSO: CARD FILE
      - Plans of work. Descriptions of proposed, pending, or completed writing projects, 1932-1962 (Folder 4)
    - Announcements and printed matter, 1927-1934 (Folder 5)
    - Bibliography, 1934 (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1920-1965 (Folder 7-8)
      - Abbot, Mary (agent), 1959-1961 (Folder 9)
      - Farrar, John, 1923-1952 (Folder 10)
      - Farrar and Rinehart (publishers), 1932-1947. (Box 56, Folder 1-3)
        Includes contracts and financial statements
      - Lieber, Maxim (agent), 1934-1940 (Folder 4)
      - Rollitts, Sarah (agent), 1937-1943 (Folder 5)
      - Volkening, Henry (agent), 1944-1963 (Folder 6)
    - Ghost-writing, collaborative, and translation projects.
      - Anthony, Etille. Notes and typescript (incomplete) relating to John Anthony, undated (Folder 7)
      - Bourke-White, Margaret. Typescript chapters for memoir, and a typescript copy of "Communism and Religion,", undated (Folder 8)
      - Davis, Tobe. Correspondence, speech, printed matter, memorandum, press releases, and a typescript copy of "Tobe Coller Davis: A Profile,", 1950-1952 (Box 57, Folder 1)
      - Feinberg, William. Typescripts of speeches and platform statements, printed matter, speech, and correspondence, 1942-1955 (Folder 2)
      - Grohmann, Will. Translation of an article relating to Al Copy and correspondence with Copley, 1961 (Folder 3)
      - Hendel, Julius. Speech typescripts, correspondence, bill, and press release, 1949-1956 (Folder 4)
      - Hisamatsu Hoseki Shinochi. Translation of a poem and correspondence with Al Copley and another, 1962 (Folder 5)
      - Holty, Carl. Typescript outline for memoir, 1951 (Folder 6)
      - Institute For Social Research. (Folder 7-9)
        Includes notes and reports
      - Kross, Anna M. Correspondence, notes, and contract, 1947 (Folder 10)
      - Mayakovsky, Vladimir. Typescript and printed copies of poems (in Russian and English), and a typescript copy of "Summary of October 1917, ", circa 1931 (Folder 11)
      - Miller, Jerome. Holograph and typescript, 1960 (Folder 12)
      - Millner, Simon. Typescript drafts of "Soviet Art," press release, flyer, and correspondence with Millner, 1941-1951 (Folder 13-17)
      - Milner, Lucille. Draft typescript fragments of The Education of An American Liberal, promotional material, and correspondence with Roger Baldwin, Arthur Garfield Hayes, Harry S Truman, Milner, and others, 1941-1959 (Box 58, Folder 1-4)
      - Naft, Stephen. Typescript copy of "Don Quixote of Rector Street," and letter by Naft, undated (Folder 5)
      - O'Dwyer, Paul. Typescript copies of speeches, 1947 (Folder 6)
      - O'Dwyer, William. Typescript and mimeograph copies of speeches, 1939-1942 (Folder 7)
      - Pilynak, Boris
        - "About Dreniasha, Member of the Moscow Soviet, and a Game of Chess," Typescript, undated (Folder 8)
        - "The Birth of Soviet Rivers," Typescript, undated (Folder 9)
        - "Farewell to America," New Masses, Printed copy and typescript fragment, 1931 Sept. (Folder 10)
        - "Fidelity," Typescript, undated (Folder 11)
        - "First and Last Love," Typescript, undated (Folder 12)
        - "Mountain Wind," Typescript, undated (Folder 13)
        - "The Russian Story," Screenplay typescript and outline, circa 1931 (Folder 14)
        - "Ye Shall Sow the Wind," Typescript, undated (Folder 15)
        - Untitled manuscript comparing the United States and the Soviet Union, Typescript, undated (Box 59, Folder 1)
        - Untitled manuscript relating to Pilynak's American trip, Typescript, undated (Folder 2)
      - Richter, Hans. Invitation, printed matter, notes relating to Richter's films and avantgarde film generally, and typescript screenplay outline for "Dreams That Money Can Buy,", 1947-1957 (Folder 3)
        SEE ALSO: CORRESPONDENCE FILE/Richter, Hans
      - Rose Fried Gallery. Press releases, 1956 (Folder 4)
      - Ruml, Beardsley. Book proposal, holograph outline, letters, mimeograph article relating to Ruml, and speech by Ruml, 1943-1945 (Folder 5)
      - Smedley, Agnes. Typescripts relating to China and letter by Smedley, circa 1943 (Folder 6)
      - Soviet Union. Relates to the Soviet exhibition at the World's Fair. Financial records, pamphlet, and correspondence with Isidor Schneider and others, 1939 (Folder 7)
      - Von Wiegand, Charmion (Mrs. Joseph Freeman). Notes and printed article entitled "David Alfaro Siquieros," New Masses, 1934 May 1. (Folder 8)
      - Williams, Albert Rhys. Relates to Rhys' memoirs and the Russian Revolution of 1917. Notes, book proposal, outline, and correspondence with Williams and others, 1955-1956 (Folder 9-10)
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments
      - General
        - Undated (Box 60, Folder 1-5)
        - 1916-1955 (Folder 6-17)
        - 1956-1961 (Box 61, Folder 1-9)
        - 1961-1963 (Box 62, Folder 1-5)
        - 1964-1965 (Box 63, Folder 1-2)
      - Autobiographical material, 1929-1963 (Folder 3)
    - Notebooks
      SEE ALSO: "Forbidden Tree," 1939-1964, for additional autobiographical notebooks
      - 1934-1946 (Folder 4-7)
      - 1947-1963 (Box 64, Folder 1-3)
  - "The American Intelligentsia and the Working Class," Typescript, undated (Folder 4)
  - "The Argument," Autobiographical writing. Typescript, undated (Folder 5)
  - "The Argument, " undated Autobiographical writing. Typescript, 1915-1916 (Folder 6)
  - "The Atrocities of German Fascism," Typescript, undated (Folder 7)
  - "The Brass Ring," Outline for a novel. Typescript, undated (Folder 8)
  - Comments on Francis Bacon, The Sirens and Other Fables, undated Typescript (incomplete) (Folder 9)
  - "Folk Art and Handicrafts," Section omitted from Voices of October? Typescript, undated (Folder 10)
  - "From the Finland Station," Autobiographical writing. Typescript, undated (Folder 11)
  - "A Full, Rich, Beautiful Life," Comments on a newspaper report on the Seventh All-Union Conference of the Young Communist League in Moscow. Typescript, undated (Folder 12)
  - "Germany: Key to Europe," Holograph outline, undated (Folder 13)
  - "Helen," Early autobiographical writing. Typescript with holographic sections, undated (Folder 14)
  - "Journey Through Sleep: A Case History," Typescript, undated (Folder 15)
  - "Medieval Europe," Extensive typescript notes, undated (Folder 16)
  - "The Middle Class Under Socialism," Typescript and notes, undated (Folder 17)
  - "Notes on the Evolution of Bourgeois Culture," Extensive typescript notes, undated (Folder 18)
  - "An Outline of Revolutionary Poetry in the U.S.A.," Typescript, undated (Folder 19)
  - Review of R. Palme Dutt, Fascism and Social Revolution, Typescript, undated (Folder 20)
  - Review of Max Lerner, Public Journal: Marginal Notes on Wartime America, Typescript, undated (Folder 21)
  - Review of Lewis Mumford, The Condition of Man, Typescript, undated (Folder 22)
  - Review of D. N. Pritt, The Zinoviev Trial, Typescript, undated (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Review of Max Shachtman, Behind the Moscow Trial, Typescript, undated (Folder 2)
  - "The Slave of the Future," Short story. Typescript (incomplete), undated (Folder 3)
  - "The Three Hats," Short story. Typescript, undated (Folder 4)
  - Untitled script, Typescripts, undated (Folder 5)
  - "Variations on a Theme," Typescript, undated (Folder 6)
  - "The Wedding," Short story. Typescripts, undated (Folder 7)
  - "Weschester [sic] Nocturne," Short story. Typescript, undated (Folder 8)
  - "Writers of Tomorrow," Proposed television or radio program. Typescript outline, undated (Folder 9)
  - "Tales," Short story collection. Holograph notebook, 1912-1915. (Folder 10)
  - "Plato," Typescript, 1919. (Folder 11)
  - "Twisted Testimony," Review of Wilfrid Thorley, Fleurs-de-Lys: A Book of French Poetry Freely Translated into English Verse. Typescript, 1920 (Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous literary notes and stories, 1921-1924
    - Notebook (Folder 13)
  - "The Life and Work of Adam Bimbo," Autobiographical writing. Holograph notebooks, 1922 (Folder 14)
  - "An American Version of the Penitent Nobleman," Typescript, 1922 February (Folder 15)
  - "The Tyranny of Women," Liberator, 1922 Aug. Review of D. H. Lawrence, Aaron's Rod. Typescript and letters, 1922-1925 (Folder 16)
  - "Don Juan at Fifty," Liberator, Typescript, 1922 September (Folder 17)
  - "A Blind Rebel in a Trap," Liberator, Typescript and printed copy, 1923 April. (Folder 18)
  - "A Blue Print of Utopia," Liberator, Review of Scott Nearing, The Next Step. Typescript, printed copy, and letter, 1923 April (Folder 19)
  - "Disciplined Eagerness," Liberator, Review of Genevieve Taggard and Thomas Seltzer, For Eager Lovers. Typescript and printed copy, 1923 April (Folder 20)
  - "Kicking the Seats of Learning," Liberator, Review of Upton Sinclair, The Goose-Step. Typescript and printed copy, 1923 April (Folder 21)
  - "What's Wrong With this Murder?" Liberator, Typescript and printed copy, 1923 May (Folder 22)
  - "Makers of America," Amalgamated Almanac, Typescripts and printed copy of isolated entries, 1924 (Folder 23)
  - Dollar Diplomacy, (co-authored with Scott Nearing), 1925
    - General. Notes, financial statements, promotional material, and correspondence with Kenneth Durant, Lewis S. Gannett, Ben W. Huebsch, Harry Laidler, Norman Thomas and others, 1924-1939. (Folder 24-25)
      SEE ALSO: CORRESPONDENCE FILE/Nearing, Scott
    - Printed copy of Spanish translation, 1926 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - "By Freighter to Batoum," Notes and typescript, 1926 (Folder 2)
  - "Jack London," Na Literaturnon Postu (Moscow), Typescripts, 1926 (Folder 3)
  - "Realism in American Fiction," Preface to Russian translation of Nathan Asch, The Office. Typescripts (in English and German), 1926 (Folder 4)
  - "The Associated Press," Typescripts and a Russian flyer with a note by Kenneth Durant, 1926 February (Folder 5)
  - "A Revolutionary Artist: A Note on Louis Lozowick," Daily Worker, Typescript, 1926 March 21 (Folder 6)
  - "Jack London als 'Revolutionar,'" Rote Fahne, Typescript, printed copy, and letter (in German), 1926, 1926 August (Folder 7)
  - "Der Vagabund: Eine Geschichte ohne Ende..." Deutsche Kolonialgreuel, Printed copy (in German), 1926 October 28 (Folder 8)
  - "Der Unfang einer schoneren Welt," Rote Fahne, Typescript, printed copy, and clipping, 1926 (in German), 1926 December 25 (Folder 9)
  - "American Questions and Answers," TASS dispatch from Moscow. Typescript, 1926-1927 (Folder 10)
  - "A Poets Olympiad," Written in Moscow. Typescript, 1926-1927. (Folder 11)
  - "American Revolutionary Literature," Typescript, 1927. (Folder 12)
  - "Blood in Kantstrasse," Typescript, 1927. (Folder 13)
  - "The Life and Death of Sacco and Vanzetti," Novy Mir, Printed copy (in Russian), 1927. (Folder 14)
  - "Heinz--A Story," New Masses, Typescript and printed copy, 1927 Jan. (Folder 15)
  - "The Gentleman from Arkansas," Rote Fahne, Written in Moscow. Typescript (in English) and printed copy (in German), 1927 February 1 (Folder 16)
  - "Poetry and Common Sense," New Masses, Typescript and printed copy, 1927 May. (Folder 17)
  - "The Student," New Masses, Printed copy, 1927 June. (Folder 18)
  - "Traveling Hard," New Masses, Printed copy, 1927 June. (Folder 19)
  - "The Wilsonian Era in American Literature," Modern Quarterly, Typescripts, printed copy, and letter, 1927-1932, 1927 June-September (Folder 20)
  - "Below the Battle," New Masses, Typescripts and printed copy, 1927 July. (Folder 21)
  - "The New Holy Grail," New Masses, Interview with Sergei Eisenstein. Typescript and printed copy, 1927 July. (Folder 22)
  - "Bulgarian Literature," New Masses, Typescript and printed copy, 1927 Aug. (Folder 23)
  - "This Cock-Eyed World," New Masses, Printed copy, 1927 August (Folder 24)
  - "Incentives," New Masses, Printed copy, 1927 September (Folder 25)
  - "Ten Years Have Passed," New Masses, Printed copy and letter, 1927 November (Folder 26)
  - "Born Comedians," Written in Moscow. Typescripts (in English and German), 1927-1928 (Folder 27)
  - "The American Artist Lozowick," Magazine of Foreign Literature, Printed copy (in Russian), 1928. (Folder 28)
  - "Literature in the Soviet Union," Typescript (incomplete), 1928. (Folder 29)
  - "A Note on Gods of the Lightning, " Typescript, 1928. (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - "The Red Commander," New Masses, Printed copy, 1928 Jan. (Folder 2)
  - "Notes on American Literature," Communist, (2 parts). Typescripts and printed copy, 1928 August-September (Folder 3)
  - "Social Aspects of American Literature," Lecture outline. Typescript, 1928 December 7 (Folder 4)
  - "The American Theatre," Hammer, Typescript, printed copy (in Hebrew) and clipping, 1928 December-1929 January (Folder 5)
  - "All Things Considered," Holograph, 1929 (Folder 6)
  - "The Gastonia Frame-Up," Typescript, 1929? (Folder 7)
  - "The Hero of American Cartoons," 1929 Expanded version of introduction to 1929 Red Cartoons, Notes and typescripts (Folder 8)
  - Introduction to 1929 Red Cartoons, Typescript and printed copy (Folder 9)
  - "Lenin on Art," New Masses, Typescript and printed copy, 1929 January (Folder 10)
  - Review of Walter B. Pitkin, The Twilight of the American Mind, New Masses, Typescript and printed copy, 1929 January (Folder 11)
  - "Intellectuals and Revolution," New Masses, Exchange between Freeman and Egmont Arens relating to Freeman's review of Pitkin's book. Typescript and printed copies and typescript copies of letters to Walter Carmon and Arens by Freeman, 1929 February (Folder 12)
  - "Sherwood Anderson's Confusion," New Masses, Typescript and printed copy, 1929 February (Folder 13)
  - "Literary Theories," New Masses, Typescript and printed copy, 1929 May. (Folder 14)
  - "Literary Patterns," New Masses, Review of Joshua Kunitz, Russian Literature and the Jew. Typescript and printed copy, 1929 June (Folder 15)
  - TASS dispatches from Mexico, Typescripts and letter, 1929 July 22-October 11 (Folder 16-17)
  - "The Mexican Press," Typescript, 1929 July 31. (Folder 18)
  - "Prince Igor and the Dancer Maria Petrova," Short story (incomplete). Typescript, 1929 October (Folder 19)
  - "False Gods: Or the Adventures of Mona Jackson," Autobiographical writing relating to Ione Robinson. Holograph notebook, 1929-1930 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Review of Carleton Beals, The Mexican Maze, Typescript and letters, 1930 (Folder 2)
  - "Politics and Crime in the United States," Typescripts, 1930 (Folder 3)
  - Voices of October, 1930 (co-authored with Joshua Kunitz and Louis Lozowick). Draft sections, reviews, notes, and correspondence with Max Eastman, James Henle, Kunitz,Lozowick and others, 1927-1935 (Folder 4-6)
  - "Social Trends in American Literature," The Communist, Typescript and printed copy, 1930 July (Folder 7)
  - Review of Charles Yale Harrison, Generals Die in Bed, New Masses, Printed copy, 1930 July (Folder 8)
  - "Views of Soviet Russia," Virginia Quarterly, Printed copy (Folder 9)
  - "War and the Intellectuals," New Masses, Typescript and printed copy, 1930 July (Folder 10)
  - "Intellectuals in America," New Masses, Typescript and printed copy, 1930 August (Folder 11)
  - "The Secret of Success," New Masses, Printed copy., 1930 Aug. (Folder 12)
    Includes typescripts, 1930 Oct. and Nov.
  - Review of Nadezhda Krupskaya, Memories of Lenin, New Masses, Typescript and printed copy, 1930 September (Folder 13)
  - "Believe It or Not," New York Herald Tribune, Review of A. T. Vassilyev, The Ochrana: The Russian Secret Police. Typescript and printed copy, 1930 September 28. (Folder 14)
  - "A Class-Conscious Novel," New York Herald Tribune, Review of Michael Ossorgin, Quiet Street. Typescripts and printed copy, 1930 October 5. (Folder 15)
  - Review of John K. Winkler, Morgan the Magnificent: The Life of J. Pierpont Morgan, New Masses, Printed copy, 1930 October (Folder 16)
  - Review of Fred D. Pasley, Al Capone: The Biography of a Self-Made Man, New Masses, Printed copy, 1930 November (Folder 17)
  - "Merry Xmas," Typescript, 1931 (Folder 18)
  - Review of Helmut Wickel, Ein Nichts Erobert die Welt: Der Aufstieg eines Industrie-Magnaten, Typescript and letter, 1931 (Folder 19)
  - "Idealistic Tendencies," Typescripts, 1931 (Folder 20)
  - "Overture," New Masses, Typescript and printed copy, 1931 January (Folder 21)
  - "On the Literary Front," New Masses, Typescript and printed copy, 1931 January (Folder 22)
  - "The Last War--and the Next," New Masses, Typescript and printed copy, 1931 August (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - "The Titan," New Masses, Printed copy, 1931 September (Folder 2)
  - "Mrs. Grady Sees Red," New Republic, Letter to the editor. Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence with Upton Sinclair and another, 1931-1932, 1931 September 9 (Folder 3)
  - "The Well-Paid Art of Lying," New Masses, Typescript and printed copy, 1931 October (Folder 4)
  - "Fourteen Years," New Masses, Typescript and printed copy, 1931 November (Folder 5)
  - The Soviet Worker, 1932. Reviews by Edwin Rolfe and others, promotional material, miscellany, and correspondence with Harry Dana, Kenneth Durant and others, 1932-1934 (Folder 6-7)
  - "Painting and Politics: The Case of Diego Rivera," New Masses, 1932 Feb. Typescripts, printed copy, printed copy of Edmund Wilson, "Rivera's Mexican Murals," responding to Freeman's objections to an earlier article by Wilson which cited "Painting and Politics," and correspondence with Bill Brown (New Republic) and Wilson, 1932-1933 (Folder 8)
  - "Pilgrims of Confusion," New Masses, Typescript and printed copy, 1932 February (Folder 9)
  - "Two Worlds," Typescript, 1932 February (Folder 10)
  - "History and Revolution," Nation, Review of Leon Trotsky, The History of the Russian Revolution. Printed copy and correspondence, 1931-1932 (Folder 11)
  - "Bloody Monday in Dearborn," New Masses, Printed copy, 1932 April (Folder 12)
  - "The Far-Eastern Front," New Masses, Printed copy, 1932 April (Folder 13)
  - "Monopoly and Control in Industry," Virginia Quarterly Review, Typescript and printed copy, 1932 April (Folder 14)
  - "A Prophet of Doom," New Masses, Typescript and printed copy, 1932 April. (Folder 15)
  - "Times are Hard," New Masses, Printed copy, 1932 April. (Folder 16)
  - "Trotzky Again," Nation, Letter to the editor relating to comments by Benjamin Stolberg on Freeman's article, "History and Revolution." Typescript, printed copy, printed copy of Stolberg's comments, letters, and unsent letter by Freeman responding to comments by Eliena Krylenko [Eastman], 1932, 1932 May 25. (Folder 17)